If you're watching this video right now,
you've probably seen a trader online
before. You probably have heard of it
from a friend or I've seen somebody like
me on the internet that has traded. Now,
you've probably either seen some videos
on YouTube, some long form videos,
[music] some short form videos, and you
have an idea of how it works. We've
actually never executed a trade, or if
you have, you probably have done it
incorrectly. So, in this video, I
prepared for you a full video where I'm
going to take you every step of the way
on how to execute a trade correctly
[music]
from start to finish. how to take your
first trade, how to even withdraw your
profits, and just to make sure that I
attack every single angle and that I
could get every one of your possible
questions answered, about my friend
here.
>> What's going on,
>> Andy? Andy knows absolutely nothing
about trading. And I finally convinced
him to learn how to trade and actually
get [music] his first trade taken in the
markets. So, he's going to be here to
not only ask any questions that you
might have to be able to ask, but it's
almost like if I were to be teaching you
at your home, but with Andy here. So,
you're going to be interrupting me,
going [music] deeper into some parts
where he might be curious. And by the
end of this video, he's going to be able
to take his first trade exactly how you
are just by following every single one
of the steps in this video. Now, before
we get started, there might be a chance
that you might get a little lost on some
concepts that you've never heard about
before or some things that you might
seem [music] to have an idea about. And
don't worry if you don't get it at the
first glance. We're going to be here to
make sure that you understand every
single step of the way. You can always
go back and rewatch this video so you
understand [music] it to perfection. So
with that being said, let's get started.
Okay, so first things first, we're going
to be talking about trading the markets,
right? So when you think about trading
the markets, what do you think? Right?
Like you think stocks, crypto, forks,
what what do you think?
>> Uh definitely crypto.
>> Crypto.
>> Yeah, that's the that's what I know.
>> Okay. So you know crypto because you
think about Bitcoin going up,
>> correct?
>> Okay. So, what we're going to be
teaching today is going to be mainly
Forex, who's also short for foreign
exchange. So, what I'm going to be
teaching you is how to trade the foreign
exchange market. So, the foreign
exchange and every other market moves
based off of the exact same thing,
supply and demand. Bitcoin goes up if
people buy Bitcoin. Bitcoin goes down if
everybody sells Bitcoin, right? Pretty
simple, very self-explanatory. Same
thing with the stock. A stock goes up if
people buy the stock. Stock goes down if
[music] people sell a stock. And with
the currency market, it's a bit
different because people aren't [music]
actually buying dollars, right? You
can't just go and buy a bunch of euros
and save it and expect for it to go up
in value. When you trade the currency
market, you're actually just betting
that it's going to get slightly stronger
or slightly weaker. And that's going to
be measured in pips and other points of
measurings where we'll talk about that
later in the video.
>> Pips. Yeah, pips. Pips. We'll talk about
it later in the video. Don't worry,
it'll it'll make sense. Which is uh PIP
is short for point and percentage. is
just how you measure it. Don't worry,
we'll get all that until later in the
video.
>> I already lost. We just started.
>> No, no, no, no. All right. So, Forex is
just foreign exchange and the money
comes from the volume that is being put
into the markets. You're basically
betting that it's going to go up or
betting that it's going to go down. It's
not like Bitcoin or like the stock
market which is based off of supply and
demand. It is, but it isn't. It's just
slightly different and it's more off of
the institutional markets.
>> So, you have an idea. The foreign
exchange market moves about $6.7
trillion dollars worth of currency every
single day compared to the stock market
which is about two to 300 billion.
>> So the foreign exchange market is much
larger than the stock market with a lot
more opportunity. Another big difference
is that it's open 245. Stock market is 9
to5 Monday through Friday. Crypto is
24/7 but there's higher cost to trading
it. Many other things that we'll be
getting on to this video.
>> Sounds good. So, any questions with the
forex market and how it actually works
and where the money comes from?
>> No, just
>> and to add to that, when you trade the
currency market, you don't ever actually
[music] own anything, right? When you
buy Bitcoin, you actually own the
digital currency. If it goes up, it goes
up with it. If you were to buy a stock,
for example, let's say you buy Tesla,
when you buy Tesla and the stock goes
up, so does your portfolio, right? So,
it goes in correlation with the money
that you invested into it. With trading
currency, that's very different. You
don't just buy a certain currency and
expect for it to go up. You have to bet
for certain periods of time that it will
go up at these micro pips, at these
microcurrency decimals. And when you
trade that with leverage and all this
other stuff that we'll talk about in
this video is how you actually make
money from the markets. Since there's so
much money being put into the currency
market, you make money off of the big
institutions moving the market. So, you
don't actually make money if a currency
goes up or down in value. You're just
betting that it actually goes up or down
in value for a certain period of time
for a certain price. Now, the simplest
analogy that I can put to this is, for
example, let's say you have two
fighters, right? Let's say you have Mike
Tyson and then Muhammad Ali. Who are you
going to pick?
>> Tyson.
>> Tyson. Okay. So, let's say that Mike
Tyson and Muhammad Ali are fighting and
the first three rounds you're going to
bet that Mike Tyson wins.
>> Okay?
>> And I bet that Muhammad Ali [music] in
the next three rounds is going to win.
Now, inevitably, one of them is going to
win because in this example, nobody can
get knocked out. So, when Mike Tyson
wins, you win. You get your money and at
no point did you own Mike Tyson for any
period of time. Trading the currency
market is the exact same. Let's say you
have the US dollar versus the great
British pound. When you trade, let's say
the dollar versus the pound, you're
betting that it's going to get stronger
for a certain period of time, but at no
point do you actually ever own the
currency or when you bet against it. So,
it's the exact same thing. [music] The
only difference is that with these
fighters, it goes on for weeks, months,
decades, years to come. It never ends.
It's like a fight that never ends and
you're just betting that it's going to
win for a certain period of time. And
the stats of the fighters is reflected
based off of how many punches, how many
jabs, how many knockdowns. And the stats
in trading is represented in [music]
charts. And we trade these patterns in
charts. So, if I see that Mike Tyson has
had three consecutive wins and he's
knocked down Mike Tyson five times, I'm
going to bet that the next run he might
knock them out again. Now, with the
dollar versus the pound is the same
thing. If I'm seeing that the dollar is
being stronger versus the great British
pound for 3, four weeks at a time, I can
expect that this following week could
also continuously be stronger. It's just
a pattern being reflected based off of
charts.
>> Okay, that's pretty easy. Just basically
whatever repeats itself, just go with
it.
>> Correct. Okay, so now that you
understand how the markets work and how
it's basically a constant battle between
one currency pair and [music] the other
that the fight never ends, basically
betting that one's going to go up for a
certain period of time, go down for a
certain period of time. You need to
actually see these charts somewhere so
you can see these patterns to actually
make that bet that it will get stronger
or get weaker.
>> Now, where you actually go and look at
these charts is going to be here. It's
going to be trading view. So trading
view is where you actually see the
patterns in the markets. So trading view
for example is a platform I'd say by
used by 99% of traders where you can go
and analyze your [music] charts. So you
come here, you search up any market. For
example, let's just do the basic Euro
USD, right? Go to EuroUSD. And once you
open up a chart, you're going to be
reflected with this, right? So,
>> I saw that you uh before you click this
open, there was a bunch of things on the
side that has said EURUSD. Like, does it
matter what you want to click on?
>> No, you can click on any market, right?
So, once you have the chart, you can
just click here and then you can just
type for example, let's say USD versus
GBP, right? So, here would be the euro
versus the pound. That's just one
example. Um, if you were to go ahead and
get, let's say, the USD versus the
Japanese yen, you can search up Bitcoin
here. This is just a platform where
you're going to be able to see the
chart.
>> Okay.
>> So, at no point do you ever execute the
trade on this platform.
>> Got it.
>> All right. So, here you're just going to
look at the chart, make an analysis
whether it should go up or should go
down.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> At first glance, this probably looks
like Chinese.
>> Well, dude, it's up and down, red, red
and green.
>> Yeah. See, but it's actually a lot
simpler than that. There's a series of
confluences and a series of patterns
that we look for that will let us to
understand where it should go up again
or where it should go down again. So for
example, if you look here to your right
hand side, you're going to see how you
have the market will automatically
separate to you the indices. It'll
separate for you some stocks. It'll
separate for you some futures and say
for separate for you some forex pairs
and some crypto. So, you can analyze
pretty much every market that you can
come up with and you're going to be able
to make a logical decision on why it
should go up or go down. Now, I know at
first glance this might seem pretty over
overwhelming, right? There's a lot of
buttons. There's a lot of different
options features and it might create a
lot of confusion, but you really only
need
10% of what you're seeing. Everything
that is on this Trading View platform is
just to show you different types of way
to read the market. You really only need
a certain amount of tools. And it's very
important that you know this at first
glance because you will actually be
spending 95% of your time when you are
trading here. Here's where you're going
to do your analysis. Here's where you're
going to determine if you want to buy or
sell a trade. So, you need to make sure
that this is clean and you're only
focusing on what you should be focusing.
Picture this as if it were to be your
desktop at your office,
>> right? So, your desktop, your your
cubicle, your workspace needs to be
clean. You need to have only the
essential things that you need to have
so you can focus on work. If you have a
bunch of extra stuff, it's going to take
away from what you're doing. So, that's
exactly what this is right here. Right?
So, over here at the top section, this
is just again, you can just search up
other markets. You can type here any
other market that you possibly want to
trade. for example, the great British
pound versus the Japanese yen. Next to
that, you're going to have this plus
symbol, which once again, it's the same
thing. You can just add the currency
pair that you want to trade. Next to
that, you have this D, which is also an
abbreviation for the daily time frame.
And these are all the different time
frames that will pop up. This is so you
can see the exact same act, the exact
same market that you're looking at in
just a different time frame. So for
example, every single one of these
candlesticks right now is a daily
candlestick. So it takes 24 hours for
every single one of these candlesticks
to form. If I were to go to let's say
the 4 hour, every single one of these 4
hours candlesticks take four hours to
form. All of that all the way down to
the one minute time frame. So each and
every single one of these candlesticks
is a one minute.
>> Okay,
>> does that make sense?
>> Which leads up to like the day.
>> Correct. Yes. That's why like for
example a day is like one long stick and
another one's like two STS.
>> Correct. Correct. So for example, let's
say this candlestick right here, this
daily candlestick. [snorts]
>> If we were to go down to the 4 hour, 2
hour, 1 hour, 30 minute, it's basically
just breaking down this one candlestick.
Got it?
>> Well, it's also breaking down the whole
entire chart, but what you see in the
most recent would be this candlestick
being broken down in half 24 times if
it's every hour, so on and so forth.
This next option up here is just
different formats on how to actually
look at the charts. You can look at the
charts in a in a line format. You can
look at it in a step line. All of this
here is literally just representing the
exact same GBPUSD at just a the exact
same price. So you can look at it in the
baseline, the highs and lows, and the
volume footprint. These are all
neverending different formats on how to
look at the actual chart. The way and
the only way we will look at it is in
the candlesticks. So you just put a
little star here next to the
candlesticks and that's all that you
ever need to focus on is the actual
candlestick way on how to look at the
chart. Everything else is just a
different format. Imagine like if you
were to have a sentence that says good
morning, how are you in 50 different
languages?
>> It means the exact same thing. You're
just speaking it in 50 different
languages. That's exactly what this is
here.
>> That looks cleaner.
>> This looks a lot cleaner. It's a lot
simpler. This is the traditional way on
how to trade. These are the Japanese
candlesticks. So, these all say the
exact same thing in just different
languages. Right [snorts] next to that,
we have the indicator section. Picture
this, the neverending dictionary of what
possible indicators you could have. You
could type here any type of indicator.
It will pop up. You never really go to
the dictionary when you want to look for
something, but it's just added here,
right? Not a feature you ever use. You
have after that the saving section where
you can just pretty much save your
screenshots. You have the alerts where
you place your alarms if you want to be
notified when price gets to a certain
point. And then you have the replay
button which the replay button is
typically used to back test and to
determine if your strategy works. H I
don't really recommend this button. And
it just creates false perception as to
what real trading is because you can
back test let's say a year's worth of
price in about 2 minutes
>> which is not realistic because it will
take you a whole year to actually trade
that and then it gives you false
perception of patience in trading how
long these trades actually take to get
to your takerit or your stop loss. So I
don't really recommend
>> so just use it to like look at the most
recent trade you took and see what's
wrong with it.
>> Correct. Yeah, I would do it to back
test the most recent trade, but not if
you go back a year or two. Next is you
have this little arrow button, which is
the back and forth picture. Pretty much
you draw a line like this or you draw a
bunch of different lines and you want to
go back, just go back, right? It's like
a
>> delete.
>> Delete pretty much. Or if you want to
bring it back, just go forward.
>> Okay,
>> pretty simple.
>> Next to that is all different features,
which is save, quit, search, settings,
full screen mode, take a snapshot,
trade, and publish. I've been using
Trading View for the last seven years.
I've never used any of these buttons up
here, so I wouldn't be able to tell you
what it is. This is almost like u it's
almost like a an engine of a car. And uh
you know, you don't really need to know
what every single component of the
engine is. You just need to know brake,
throttle, air conditioning, music, the
basics, right? So all of these other
buttons I have no idea what it is. Watch
list is what we have here. Are different
types of watch list that we have. So
once again, you can add these different
watch lists to, you know, you can upload
a picture, create a new list, clear it,
rename it, make a copy. I've never used
any of these right here. Personally,
myself, I don't know what any of these
buttons do. This right here just lets
you know what symbol you're trading, the
last price. So, this is what the current
price of every single one of these
symbols are. And this is I have no idea.
>> I believe you can change it here. Yeah,
like you can just take it off here,
change and change and then you're just
left with the currency pair and then the
price. And if you want to have this be
here, you want to have it very far
tucked away or you can move it all the
way to the left. This is just again you
want to clean up your workspace and only
focus on what you need to focus.
Obviously here you have all the
different types of currency pairs you
want to if you want to go ahead and add
a currency pair just click here add once
again search it up and it will add
automatically. Let's say we want to add
the Tesla stock. We just come Well, we
already have it, right? Let's say we
want to add a different one. This one,
we just come here. We click add, and it
would add it. Since we're on the free
version right now, it's not letting us.
Continuing to the bottom, I don't know
what any of these options are here. If I
were to move this up, obviously, this
would give us an assumption of what
Trading View believes could happen next.
It's going to basically tell us their
overall understanding of it. But I have
no idea what any of this means. Usually
I always have this all the way down and
I have the markets tucked very very far
to the right. Right. This section right
here is just the different pricing on
this current market. So for example,
we're on Euro USD right now. But if we
were to go to gold, for example, this is
just gold being at 4900
almost at 5,000 creating new all-time
highs, which is crazy. And these are
just different price points of once upon
a time once gold was there. Uh going
down to this section right here. This is
basically the days. You know, you can
just drag it so you can get a more clear
version of the chart. You can see how
this was February. This was the start of
the year, December, November. Just dates
everything and then it gives you the
price. These bars are very unnecessary.
I always go to style and I just take
them off. It's not necessary at all. You
just double click them. I've never used
them in my life, so I wouldn't be able
to tell you how it works. Everything
down here, I guess just different
formats on how to actually look at the
markets. I've never used this ever in my
life. If you drag this up, these are
just different recommendations from
Trading View, different trading panels.
I've never used any of them. I have no
idea how it works. And this is just the
time of when the market is right now.
This section over here is where things
could be a bit never ending, right?
These are all different tools. Imagine
as if you were to have the desk to your
cubicle and you have a big open space.
And on that big open space, you have
space to add anything you want to put a
plant. You can put one of those cool
gadgets that move up and down, a phone
holder, a little speaker, a picture of
your family, whatever you want. You can
put there. You can get as creative as
you want. Or you can leave it empty.
Well, this is basically that. These are
the never-ending different types of
tools that you can have to analyze the
market. These are different types of
things that you can have in your desk
that entertain you while you're at work
or motivate you and give you a purpose.
These are different types of tools that
you can analyze the markets. Some tools
are very essential. Other tools are not.
The main tools that are going to be
essential will be the trend line. Now,
I'm only going to talk about what is
necessary and what is not necessary
because what is not necessary is no
point in talking about it.
>> Of course,
>> right? All you're going to need is just
the trend line, a horizontal line,
horizontal array, and that's it.
Everything else here, I wouldn't be able
how to explain what it is. It's just
simply not necessary. Next, after that,
you have a bunch of different patterns
like the Fibonacci, the GAN. I have no
idea how this works, so I can't really
speak on it. After that, the only other
pattern that I ever really use is going
to be the head and shoulders. Just click
on a star. It will automatically pop up
to your favorites box here. And then
after that, you're going to have your
projections area. These are very
important. The long position and the
short position are going to be the only
projection tools that you need. This
will measure your trade. We'll get into
that in just a second. Okay. So, these
are going to be your long and short
positions. Projections for when you
enter a trade.
>> What's short and long?
>> Okay. So, long is when you enter a trade
as a buy, right? Picture long. You're
going up. That's when you buy a
position. So, if I were to click this
right here, place it on the chart. This
is your long risk-to-reward tool. This
is your stop-loss area. This is your
take-profit area. And then your short
position is basically the opposite.
Picture short going down sell. So
whenever
>> green is good, red's bad.
>> Yes. Red is basically loss. Green is
basically profit. And then you have
profits when you go down and you have
profits when you go up.
>> Got it. So long is you're buying and
short you're selling.
>> Short you're selling. Correct. Correct.
>> Next. After that, you pretty much just
have another area where it's just
charting up. Basically here, the only
one that is really necessary is just the
rectangle which you're going to be using
for areas of interest, support and
resistance. Don't worry, all that will
make sense in just a second. Everything
that after here I honestly I have no
idea how to use. Everything is very much
unnecessary. These are all just
different formats on how to actually
measure price. You want to zoom in and
out, magnet things that I just never
use. And then the last but not least is
this section up here. This just once
again reminds you what type of currency
pair you're using, the type of time
frame you're on, and the price to sell,
and the price to buy. This right here, I
wouldn't even be able to tell you what
it is. It's just always moving as soon
as you move the crosshair. So, let me
just double click this down here once
again, and let remove it just so you can
focus on what is needed to be focused
on. Right? So, this right here is now
your workspace. So now you know in your
workspace the only tools you need to
focus on are these tools right here that
once you click on the star they'll
automatically pop up here and the
currency markets that you're going to be
trading or any markets that you will be
trading are here to your right hand
section. So this is your workspace and
the only things that you need to focus
on.
>> And obviously when you create an account
that you log in that little bar section
stays there the whole time. Doesn't
matter if you close it up.
>> Correct. Yeah. Once you actually log in
and you create your account this is
whatever you whatever you chart up here.
Let's say if you were to put some lines
like this, you were to put a horizontal
line here, it's going to stay there,
right? Picture this as your cubicle.
Once you go into your cubicle, you do
whatever it is. If you want to leave
your plant there, you don't water it for
3 days. Once you leave and close the
door, no one's going to go back in
there, right? That's that's your spot.
This is exactly the exact same. This is
your workspace. It's private. Whatever
you put in here is just yours. So, this
is where you're going to analyze if
you're interested in entering a trade or
not. This is where you're going to
determine if it's good or if it's not
good. Now, when you determine that it's
good to enter a trade, let's say, for
example, at this point, you want to buy
this market at this point that we are
right here. Let's say you want to buy
this position right here. You want to
take a buy. Well, how do you do that?
Well, back in the day when you would
want to trade, I'm sure you've seen the
videos of the New York Stock Exchange,
people on the phone talking to people.
>> Well, it's not like that anymore, right?
World has changed. It's a lot more
convenience and available to anybody to
do it. So for you to take a trade, all
you have to do is instead of you calling
a broker and telling them, "Hey, I want
to enter this position and they enter it
for you." You just go and create an
account on these brokers and then you
enter the position yourself.
>> So I recommend two different types of
brokers. You have your first broker
which is going to be LQ Markets and then
you have your second broker which is
going to be 1X Trade. Both of these
brokers offer very competitive market
spreads which is the cost to enter a
trade. Both of them offer different
types of leverage that based off of your
account. But long story short, you can
do your own due diligence on which
brokers you want to execute your trades
on and deposit the money into. These are
just the ones that I recommend. And this
is where you would go ahead and deposit
your money into these platforms and
actually go ahead find the market that
you want to trade and then enter the
trade. You you would deposit into here,
take a trade, and you would withdraw
your money from this actual platform.
>> Okay. So basically it's like the a bank
holding my money like deposit they hold
it for me and then win or lose a trade
whatever.
>> Yeah. Correct.
>> They just I contact them through
whatever and the title.
>> Yeah. This is basically like a bank. You
deposit money into a bank if [music] you
want to go ahead and pay someone.
>> Okay.
>> You you wire them, you sell them, cash
app, whatever it is. Just here you're
not paying anybody. You're just
depositing into here and you execute the
trade in here.
>> Sounds good.
>> So yeah, this is like where the money is
stored and this is where you withdraw,
deposit and everything is from here. So
backtrack a little bit is on you. Uh I
see it says leverage. It says one to
500. What what's that?
>> Yeah. So I mean leverage is probably one
of the most competitive parts of these
different types of brokers and it's what
gives you an edge over a different one.
And the leverage is probably the most
important because it gives you the most
access to your money, right? Let's say
right now you're going to go and create
a brand new bank account and you deposit
$10,000 into your bank account. Right
away you won't have access to your bank
account. I mean you won't have full
access to those $10,000. You can't just
send out the full 10,000 if it's a new
account
>> or you can't just get credit against
those funds. And if you do, it's just a
onetoone, right? You will never get 500
times to what your money is. Well, in
here in these trading markets, they give
you leverage on your money and ex
availability to it right away. So, what
leverage does it gives you more access
to your money plus you get to leverage
against it without overexposing
yourself. So, if you want to take a
trade risking, let's say you deposit 100
bucks, you have buying power with those
100 bucks as if it were to be $5,000,
>> but you only are actually risking those
$100. Okay?
>> If you go to deposit 100 bucks in the
bank, all you really have is just a h
100 bucks. Got it.
>> Here, you have full availability to your
100 bucks times 500. It's just a very
>> strong way on how to grow small accounts
and trading. And that's why I personally
got started trading in the foreign
exchange to start off because every
other type of market whether it's
stocks, whether it's crypto, they don't
give you big leverage like how the
currency markets do.
>> Okay. And obviously there's more like
not just 500. It's different.
>> Yeah. 1 to 500 is typically the max.
>> There's others that are 1 to 1,000, but
typically you don't want to go that high
because then it's just way too high. I'd
say anywhere from like 1 to 100 to 1 to
500 is more than avail like more than
enough. So now coming back into the
markets, now that you understand that
this is where you analyze the markets
and for you to go ahead and execute a
trade, you need to use one of these two
brokers, right? But before you execute
the trade, you have to make an analysis
if it makes sense if it's going to go up
or going to go down, right? So it's very
simple. Trading is no different than
fishing or surfing. We're going to go
with the surfing analogy because it's by
far the most effective and by far the
most accurate. Let's just picture
ourselves that we're surfers, right?
Have you ever surfed in your life? No.
>> No.
>> Never caught a wave, dude.
>> Never. What What is your concept of
surfing?
>> Just grab a board and ride that wave.
>> You ride the wave, right?
>> What's the most important thing about
riding a wave?
>> Catching the right one
>> and understanding what direction it's
going, right? Because if you stand in
front of the ocean and you're looking at
the waves, if the waves are going east
rather than west, you're going to surf
the waves to the east. It doesn't
logically make sense to want to surf
west because the waves just simply
aren't going that way. Trading is very
different. If we can determine that the
trend which is equivalent to the waves,
right? If the trend of the market is all
headed to the upside, well, it would
logically make sense to continue going
to the upside, right? So, for example,
we do something that is called topdown
analysis. What what comes to your mind
when you think about that?
>> Basically, just look at something and
study it from the top to bottom.
>> That's exactly what it is.
>> So, we're going to look at this market
from the top down. And when I mean top
down, I mean from the higher time frame
to the lower time frame.
>> So we have our weekly time frame, we
have our daily time frame, and then we
have our 4our time frame. So we're going
to start from the highest time frame.
Start from the top down. We're going to
start from the weekly, then go to the
daily, then go to the 4 hour. So when we
start off on the weekly time frame on
this market, what is at first glance
that you think this market is doing?
What is the last point of price? Is the
market going up or is the market going
down?
>> It's going up,
>> right? Right. Looks like it.
>> Looks like it, right? Well, that's
exactly what it's doing.
>> Okay,
>> pretty simple. So, we're going to label
this as a high point, right? This right
here is going to be a high point. We're
going to call this
the high, right? So, this is the high
point in the market on the weekly time
frame, right? Weekly time frame. Now,
that is our analysis on the weekly time
frame. Then, we go down to the daily.
Now the daily time frame, what do you
believe is happening on the daily time
frame? Is the market going up or is the
market going down?
>> I want to say keep going up just based
on like you know say high weekly looks
the same.
>> Looks the same, right?
>> Yeah.
>> Well, it's because it is. [laughter]
It's the exact same thing. The daily
time frame is also at a high point. So
here we have our weekly high and then
we're also going to add here let's call
it a daily high. Right? So clearly we
have the weekly is bullish which bullish
means up bearish means down. So the
weekly is bullish the daily is bullish.
They're both at a high. Let's see what
the 4 hour is doing. Right.
>> So on the 4hour time frame what does
this look like on the 4 hour?
>> Same thing.
>> Same thing. Follow the pattern. So the 4
hour happens to also be at a high. Cool.
Pretty easy, pretty self-explanatory,
right? So we have the 4 hour
is at a high
>> to the trade. That's it.
>> Yes and no. Right. Okay. Right. So
obviously that would be at first glance
what would make the most sense, right?
You have all these time frames that are
going up. Take the trade. Yes and no. So
picture this right now. You have gotten
to the beach and now that you're at the
beach, the wave that is closest to you
is going east. The wave that is in the
middle where people typically don't go
to because it's pretty deep are going
east. And then the waves way back over
there where the surfers get on and the
ones before that are also going east. So
you can 100% [snorts] determine that all
of these waves are going east.
>> Okay?
>> So it makes sense to go surf east,
right? So you already eliminated half of
the problem. People can't distinguish
between clicking the buy button or the
sell button and you've just eliminated
the sell button completely. So all you
have to do is now find the right point
where it logically makes sense to buy.
>> So making a mistake of entering in the
wrong direction is already out of the
picture by just finding the high point
in the market which very you just did in
2 minutes
>> literally. So now that we know that
everything is at a high, we've already
eliminated the hardest part to finding
if we want to buy or sell. Now where do
we enter the trade is the big issue. So
you just said, "Okay, we're ready to
enter the trade." And that's probably
the biggest mistake traders make.
>> They might be right understanding the
direction of the trade. And I'm sure a
lot of traders out there are typically
right about the direction by the end of
the week, by the end of the day, but
they never actually know where exactly
to enter. So that's where we go on to
our next step which is going to be the
area of interest. So first step is going
to be the trend which is understanding
where the market is headed. The next
step is going to be area of interest.
This is where we are literally going to
be interested in entering the position
whether we want to enter a buy or
whether we want to enter a sell. But the
first step is understanding where the
market is headed. Without understanding
where the market is headed we cannot
have a trade. Right. Got it.
>> So area of interest. What does an area
of interest consist of? Well, an area
cons an area of interest consists of
support and resistance.
Support and resistance,
supply and demand zone,
order blocks,
roof,
and ceiling. Now, I know at first glance
this might seem some type of Chinese,
right?
>> Yeah.
>> What is support and resistance? What is
supply and demand zone? What is order
blocks?
>> We're building blocks.
>> No, we're not building blocks just yet.
It's going to look like it, but it's
not. Order blocks, supply and demand,
support and resistance is all the same
thing. Roof and ceiling. When something
is a roof, what does that mean?
>> Can't pass it. It's top.
>> Correct. It's stopped. You can't pass
it. Right now, for example, if this were
to be the roof, if we were to want to
pass it, it's rejecting it. It's acting
as resistance. Let's say for whatever
magical reason, we could break through
this roof. Now, this resistance is no
longer resistance. It could then this
roof could be used as support to then
continue going to the next roof or
wherever it is that we want to go.
>> Okay?
>> So, same thing vice versa. Let's say
this is going to be the support area,
right? So, let's say let's say price is
trying to go down, right? or whatever is
trying to go down. This is I put roof
and ceiling. It's the same thing. Roof
and floor.
>> I meant to put roof and floor, right? I
never thought that.
>> Okay, good. So, this is how people know
that it's real that that you don't know,
right? So, there's a a roof which is a
ceiling and then we have the floor which
is the support. So, the roof is the
resistance, right? When price tries to
break through this resistance,
>> okay,
>> this is the roof. It can't, right? And
then this is going to be the support. So
when price tries to break through the
floor, it can't because it's the floor.
And if it were to break through it,
well, it breaks through, right?
>> So there's a big difference in between
the roof and the floor. When price is
below it, and when price is above it.
When it's above it, it should go up.
When it's below it, it should go down.
When you have a ceiling above you, you
should hit that ceiling and then come
back down. When you're above a floor,
like how we are right now, if we hit it,
we're supposed to continue to go up. Now
the support from this level which is the
floor once price breaks through it it
could be used as a ceiling to then push
price down.
>> Vice versa once you have a ceiling once
price breaks through it can use it as
support to continue going up.
>> Okay. Now, people have gotten very
creative over the last couple of years
on renaming this roof and floor to order
blocks, supply and demand zone, support
and resistance, and like myself, area of
interest.
>> Oh, so you just typed all it all mean
the same thing.
>> It's all the same thing.
>> But I want to let you know it's all the
same thing before you go out there and
you get distracted with these other
concepts that mean the same thing. It's
almost like saying that, okay, you're
going to be surfing the you're going to
be surfing the wave east and you know
some other surfer comes with a different
wording and says you're going to boogie
>> to the east coast or you're going to
handstand. It's it's all meaning the
same thing. You're going to surf this
way, right? So, now that we understand
that the area of interest is all the
same thing,
>> let me break it down in a way that's
very visual and that you can understand
it. Right? So let's picture this right
here. So let's picture price right now
is currently creating something like
this. So this is just a market that I'm
going to be drawing right here. So for
example, right here, this is this
market.
And as you can tell, where is this
market right now? Is it up or down?
>> This is going down the bottom.
>> Okay, cool. This market is going down
right now. We understand that this
market is going down, but this market
right now is going down and has run into
a support area. As you can tell here,
this is where price has previously
rejected from once we're above. So price
has come here, rejected it, come here,
rejected it, and now that it's here
again, it can potentially reject it once
again. So, this can potentially be
another time where it uses it as the
floor to then have a push to the upside
because if it's done it once, it can
definitely do it again. It can come here
and have a push to the upside like this.
So, now let's say price does have a
reaction from this area like this from
the support how it should. It's going to
run into this. What is this right here?
>> The roof.
>> Correct. That is the roof. So this right
here is going to be the roof.
And then this is going to be the floor
which is also known as support and
resistance or also known as area of
interest. Okay,
>> all of this will make sense in just a
second. So let me put this here in the
bottom so we can identify and let me put
this here in the top so we can identify.
Right? So here we have the roof and here
we have the floor. So once again, right
now we are below this roof. So we're at
the roof which is the resistance. This
is also equivalent to resistance.
And this is also equivalent to support.
This right here add the support. Right
now that we're at this resistance, do
this.
We can potentially do the exact same
thing. We can come here and then reject
the resistance and come back to the
support. Once we're at the support, we
can do the exact same thing and we can
continuously reject this for who knows
how long, right? But there will be a
time where we will break through the
resistance or break through the support.
Now, what leads that to happen could be
fundamentals, some news events that
happen, something that makes one
currency pair stronger than the other.
Who knows, right? We don't ever try and
predict when that's going to happen.
What we do is react to once it happens.
>> So, we don't care if the waves go from
east to west.
>> We just wait.
>> We just wait. Once it happens, we then
start surfing west instead of east. But
at no point will we try and predict when
that change will happen. It's too much
of a headache and it takes away from the
surfing experience as a whole. It makes
it more challenging than what it is
already. So we don't try and predict
once this changes is once it does it we
react to it. So for example this
resistance has been holding price down
for some time. Once price breaks it cool
it will break it eventually. And what we
do now as traders is we need to wait for
price to come back and retest that
resistance to then act as support. So a
resistance could be used as supports. A
support could be used as resistance.
This is very important because they go
hand in hand. One hand washes the other.
>> Okay.
>> This resistance will then be used as
support to potentially hold price up
from here to then have a continuation
push to the upside. So what was holding
price down before is now going to push
price up potentially. Right? But the
most important thing is we need to wait
for that retest. So once the market is
at a high point, we need to wait for
that retest. We cannot enter a buy
position up here because you're
basically buying too high. Picture right
now when Bitcoin hit
>> $120,000 or whatever the high point was.
Does it make sense to buy something at
the most expensive point?
>> Mhm.
>> Not really. Right. You you want to wait
for a little bit of a discount, right?
So once price comes back, you have
something to reference to previously. So
right here, once this price hits the
high, this retracement is so crucial.
One, because it gives you a discount,
gives you a better price to actually buy
this at. And two, it will confirm that
this resistance is now going to be used
as support to push price to the upside.
>> Okay.
>> Does that all that make sense?
>> Yeah. Yeah. It's just retesting the
previous like
system where it was at for a while.
>> Correct. Okay.
>> If it was holding price before, it
should now push price to the upside. So,
at this point right here, we need to
wait for price to come back, give us a
retest of the resistance to then have a
push up. So, we get the discount one and
two. So, it can hold price up. Now,
>> that's exactly what's happening us to
here on the market that you have just
identified. If you notice, if I were to
just draw out this market structure like
this, just simple market structure and
not look at the candlesticks, you're
going to notice that yes, right now
price is very obviously bullish. So,
this is the exact same market price is
right here. Price is very much at a
high, but that's exactly where you are
right now. You're at a high. You don't
want to buy at the highest point. What
you want to do is go to the [music] left
and find some resistance points, which
is also known as an area of interest to
potentially hold price to push it to the
upside. For example, this right here
could be one resistance point right
here. If we can continue to go, this
could be another resistance point right
here. Clearly, the market reacted from
there. And then we can come to this
point right here where clearly the
market has reacted previously. So all
we've done is once price has a high
point, we try and find the resistance so
price can then retest it and have a push
to the upside. It's exactly what this is
right here. Price is at a high point.
This is the high point. Now we need to
wait for that discount. This market now
being bullish, we have to wait for that
discount to come back either to this
zone to the next zone which could be
this zone or it could be this zone right
here. Right? So these are the three
possible zones that we could be
interested in entering the trade. So
picture this right now as if we were to
be the surfers and we understand that
price I mean we understand that the
ocean is coming this way is coming east.
We just need to find where we enter that
wave. Should we enter very far out?
Should we enter kind of in the middle
where there's some rocks? Should we
enter closer to shore where there's
maybe some people chilling on the beach?
That is where the decision of a beginner
trader and an experienced trader will
come in. Should we enter at the first
area of interest once price starts
having that discount? Do you want to
wait for a halfway discount or do you
want to wait for a big discount? This is
where experience, this is where
continuation of practicing will come in
and you can snipe that prediction of
when the market is actually going to
have a reaction from this zone compared
to this zone or compared to this zone.
It can also lead to an area being
stronger than the other, one area being
safer than the other. Back to the
surfing analogy is let's say the zone
which let's call this zone which is
going to be the furthest zone from where
price is technically right now.
>> Okay.
>> The furthest zone is very far out. Very
far out typically. What is far out in
the ocean?
>> Far far away.
>> But what what's in the ocean typically?
>> Water.
>> Deep.
>> No. Obviously there's sharks too. Right.
[laughter] Right. So there's obviously
sharks. So, if you go really, really,
really far out, maybe yes, you can catch
a bigger wave because obviously if you
wait for this big discount, you're going
to have a much better return, but might
be a higher risk because if you go so
far out in the ocean, there's sharks out
there, you might get eaten. Are you a
fast swimmer? Is it worth it? Is it not?
That's entirely up to you at that given
point. or do you want to play it a bit
safer and enter the trade where there's
no sharks but there's some rocks but if
the tide is really high the odds of you
falling if you fall you might not hit a
rock or you want to just play it safe
and do it right by the shore and
potentially hit someone with the board.
So these are just the three different
zones where you have to go and determine
if you want to enter the trade at that
point and it comes down to experience
and just being an experienced trader.
So, sorry. I have a question. Uh, you
see how you have the three zones. In the
last zone, you said it's a good area to
wait for it to come back, but wouldn't
that make the market like to go down
like the red arrow?
>> Yes.
>> Wouldn't that be like a different route?
>> It would mean that it it went down
temporarily just to have that discount.
But the retracement did indeed happen
because the market was bullish at that
time.
>> Okay.
>> But yes, that's a great observation.
>> Okay. So now that you determined that
you want to enter the trade at one of
these zones, your job as a trader is to
just wait. You have to wait for price to
get to these zones. Once price gets to
these zones, then you look for what is
next, which is going to be called your
entry signal. So let's say right now
you're the surfer. You have just left
the shore on your board. You're paddling
to the area that you want to enter the
trade or the area that you want to enter
the wave. So which area do you want to
pick? Pick area one, two, or three.
>> I mean, based on what you're saying,
I'll go with three.
>> You're going to go to three.
>> Yeah.
>> All right. So, you're going to go you're
going to take the risk that you could
potentially get eaten by a shark.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. You're a high-risisk surfer,
high-risisk trader. Totally fine.
>> It's going to be cool.
>> So, you have now swam past the people.
You've swam past the rocks. Now, you're
out there in the open ocean just waiting
for price to get there or waiting for
the ocean or the wave to get there for
you to enter the wave. Now once the
waves are approaching you, you can't
just enter the first wave that comes.
You need to wait for a specific entry
signal. Now that can consist of the
ocean having I'm not a surfer, right?
I'm just, you know, coming up with basic
assumption here. But you can have the
the ocean create a certain crevice and
the wave approaching you is 1 ft tall, 2
feet tall, 3 ft tall. You need to have a
very specific entry signal to enter that
wave that you repeat every single time.
So now you know you want to trade east.
You know what area you want to enter the
wave at. Now you need a specific pattern
that the wave shows you for you to
actually enter that wave. Okay?
>> It's the exact same in the markets. Once
price has come back into this area, you
need to wait for what is called an entry
signal in the candlesticks which can
consist of a series of candlestick
rejections. The main common candlestick
rejection could be something what is
called a rejection candlestick. So if we
were to just go to Google and just
search up candlestick
rejections, you're going to be led with
hundreds of different of candlesticks
rejections, right? So if we go here, you
have what is going to be called the
bearish rejection candles and then the
bullish rejection candles. It's the
candles that have the wicks. These wicks
are the tails of the market. So this
picture, that tail, that line, the
history of price. So once upon a time
price was fully a red candle in this
area like this. So this was once a full
candlestick like this and once price
filled that candlestick then what ended
up happening is that it came back down
and it actually ended up closing to the
downside. Same thing here. So a
candlestick it means that price once
made it to that area and then it didn't.
Another example is that was the highest
points of the candlestick at one point.
That was the lowest point of the
candlestick at one point and then it
ended up closing like this. That's the
that's the trail that it left. Picture
as if it were to be somebody that walked
to a certain trail this way in the snow.
So they leave a footprint this way. They
saw something there that scared them.
Could have been a bear. It could have
been a trap. And then they walked back
and they went a different direction.
Something led them that way and then
they didn't like it and they came back
the other way. Okay,
>> this is exactly what these rejections
are. And these candlesticks are
everywhere in the market. As you can
tell, that's one big candlestick
rejection. So, at one point, that
candlestick was full red or full green
to the upside. It ended up rejecting it.
And look how price came to the downside.
As you can tell, for example, right
here, these are candlesticks that have
clearly very much rejected. They were
fully up this way and then they
rejected. And these candlesticks are
everywhere. These rejection
candlesticks, literally all over the
chart. So your goal is once you're at
this area, you want for a candlestick to
have
gone all the way down and then once it
closed, it created with that candlestick
rejection like this. So it shows that
it's actually rejecting that area and
then the candlestick after that should
be a candlestick going in the continuing
direction of the trend. Got it?
>> So once it's at that area of interest,
you need to have a very specific entry
signal. Once again, there's hundreds of
different types of candlesticks,
different types of rejections. To me,
this is my favorite and the most
powerful once price is at that area of
interest.
>> So, what I just noticed that you just
show me there with those little
candlestick that you drew is basically
like coming down and then it rejects or
or Yeah. basically rejects the like the
roof and this and
>> correct [snorts]
>> ceiling the floor.
>> Correct. Yeah. So, this is a ceiling.
>> Okay.
>> A roof a resistance. It comes over here,
then price rejects it. Once price
rejects it, it uses it as support, the
floor, area of interest, whatever you
want to call it, and then it continues
to push price to the upside.
>> Got it.
>> Perfect.
>> So, now that it comes into the area,
like you said, it rejects it. When do I
know like it it it closes and goes to
another candlestick?
>> So, it depends on what time frame you
want to enter the trade. If you want to
enter it off of the daily time frame, if
you want to enter off of the 4 hour time
frame, it really depends what time frame
you want to enter off of.
>> So once, let's say you want to have the
4hour candlestick, you have to wait for
a 4hour candlestick rejection. Once that
candlestick closes is when you would go
ahead and enter the trade and then you
would have the next candlestick continue
in that direction.
>> Okay?
>> Now, keep in mind,
>> the higher the time frame, the stronger
the rejection. If I were to go down, for
example, to the one minute time frame
>> on the
>> What was that?
>> Sell snap.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. You could go down as
low as like the one second time frame,
which is it's the craziest thing ever.
>> Picture every single one of these
candlesticks literally form every 60
seconds. So, it's very easy for a
candlestick rejection to be formed. It
doesn't take much for that to happen.
>> Okay?
>> Picture that. Now, on the daily time
frame, it takes 24 hours for a whole
candlestick to have a rejection. So when
you see a rejection on the daily
candlestick takes 24 hours. It means
that it's very strong compared to the
lower time frame. So you want to make
sure that you can find your entry signal
on the higher time frame.
>> Got it?
>> Okay. So now let's say that price has
come back to this area, right? So we're
going to mark this off like this. This
is what it would look like on the
candlestick chart. So what you want for
price to do now is price to come back
into this area and price to actually
retest this area of interest so it can
have a push to the upside. M
>> so let's just hypothetically pretend
like this market has done that already.
Let's pretend like price has done this
retracement. It has given you this
rejection and you are ready to enter the
trade. Right? So this is where I feel
like a lot of people procrastinate. A
lot of people choke up and freeze up.
Not only because they don't know where
to actually enter the trade, but because
they actually overthink and panic the
whole process of taking a trade
themselves, which is probably the
easiest thing that you can possibly do.
So, I'm I'm going to walk you through
right now creating your own account.
We're going to deposit a 100 bucks and
take a trade in the market so people can
see the full experience, right?
>> Sounds good.
>> So, we're going to go here to 1x trade
for example. We use this broker in this
specific example and we'll create an
account. So, we'll come here. We're
going to create an account and we're
going to log in. We're going to walk you
through to actually depositing into this
account, right? So, let me create an
account really fast. So, we've sent an
email to my email to login. So you guys
can't see my email for privacy purposes.
I don't want my email to get blown up.
So let me actually just click on the
link so we can activate my account. Give
me one second. Okay. So now that you
have actually created your account on 1x
trade on LQ on whatever broker you
decide that you want to create your
account, this is what the inside of 1X
specifically looks like. Right? So very
self-explanatory, very simple. This is
already an account that I created. Once
you create an account and you want to
deposit your funds or create an account,
it's going to ask you to do their KYC
process. It's like any bank account,
right? You go to Chase, you go create a
bank account. You need to know who you
are and just to make sure that your
information is accurate when you go
deposit your funds, right? Very basic
information. Now, this is basically
everything is very self-explanatory.
Here you have your dashboard where you
can see the total amounts of funds that
you have deposited, withdraws, how many
trading accounts you have, the total
transaction history of how you deposited
your money, where you've withdrawn, how
many trading accounts you have, whether
you have a pro account, and the
different types of accounts, and we'll
get into all that in just a second.
Different competitive
competitions that you can host with
yourself. You can join certain
competitions if you'd like. and if you
would want to be an affiliate. So, in
the dashboard section, as you can tell,
if you were to want to deposit funds
into the platform, there's two different
ways on how to do it. Either crypto or
credit card. Everything is very
self-explanatory. Let's say you want to
choose crypto, for example. And let's
say you want to use a promo code. I have
a promo code for people. You want to get
10 15% more on your deposit on 1X. Just
use the promo code in the description
down below. You type in the promo code
here, whether it's Alex or whatever it
is that it will be in the description
later in this video and then the amount
that you want to deposit. Let's say for
example here we want to deposit 10
bucks. The minimum deposit [music] is 10
bucks and you would click deposit into
trading platform and these would be the
different types of cryptocurrency that
you could deposit in. So, you would
already need to have this cryptocurrency
some type of way on some type of
platform. And then you just transfer it
into this account. Or if you want to go
ahead and use your credit card, debit
card, or any type of card, same exact
thing. You put in the promo code here if
you want because it's obviously
optional. You put the amount that you
want to deposit into the platform, which
it's a minimum of 10 bucks. And then you
just understand that the credit card
process takes some time, right? It could
take up to 24 hours to verify and make
sure that everything is good. So you
click into deposit into your trading
platform and once you click on that then
you have different types of options how
to deposit. You have Stripe, Robin Hood,
maybe sometimes PayPal even posits
deposits pop up. So you would just click
on that and then go through that
process.
>> So I've already done that. I already
have the funds in here just so it's
faster and it's more effective for us.
So now in our dashboard area, we have
obviously a total of 100 bucks that have
been deposited. Right?
>> Now picture this right now that you have
just walked into the bank. Now that
you're inside of the bank, you have
spoke to a teller and you have KYC. So
you have given them your ID. You have
verified that you're a real person.
You're not a fugitive on the run. They
verified that you're a real person and
you just gave them $100 in cash and you
deposited into your bank account.
>> Right? So, you have $100 now in let's
call it this [music] bank account. Now,
let's say you want to go ahead and pay
somebody, right? Let's say you want to
go ahead and pay somebody for whatever
type of let's say you want to buy
this phone case, right? You want to buy
this phone case. Cost $10. Now, for you
to buy this phone case, you can't pay
them through the bank, right? You can't
send them a wire. They only take some
type of merchants. So, you have to pay
them either through Cash App, Zel, uh,
Venmo, Grillil, or PayPal, right? So,
you have to connect your bank account to
PayPal. You send the money to PayPal and
then they get their money in their
PayPal account. So, you deposit your
money into the bank and then the bank
puts it in PayPal. You can't just put
your money straight into PayPal. you
have to go through a bank. So this is
very similar when it comes to actually
taking a trade. So you don't take a
trade on the 1x platform. You need to
use a third party platform which is most
commonly the most common and the the
best one which is MetaTrader. MetaTrader
picture it as a PayPal. If you want to
pay somebody, you need to use this third
party platform.
>> If you want to take a trade, you have to
use this third party platform which is
MetaTrader. But your funds are stored
inside of this platform. Right? So now
for you to create your PayPal account,
this broker actually does it for you. So
it does all the hard work for you. So
let's say you actually want to go and
take a trade, you would create a new
account. Once you go to trading
accounts, right, you can go ahead and
open a demo account if you want. So it
could be paper money or we can do real
money. In this example, we'll use real
money because it's realistic to what you
would want to do if you want to become a
trader. You would click open an account
and then you have four different types
of accounts. You have your standard
commission free experts and Islamic
accounts. And Islamic accounts are very
unique because it's a sin to pay
interest. And that's why they have this
type of account set up. It's pretty
cool. I'm not Islamic. So, we'll just go
with the standard account in this
example. Right. Our minimum deposit is
10 bucks. And we want to select our
leverage before creating the account.
And we want to make sure that we have
the most access to our money. So, for
this example, we'll put a 1 to 500. so
we can have the most leverage, the most
availability to our funds that we can
possibly have. Go ahead and create an
account and then your accounts just
requested and received and we'll notify
you once it's created. So once your
request is approved, you will receive an
email with your new account information.
So in my email in a couple of minutes,
I'll get this new account and then there
I will get the login to log into this
account. Okay,
>> for this example purposes, we're just
going to use this account that I already
have here, which I already have
everything approved. So, I would go to
view and if I were to want to deposit
money into this account that I've just
created, I can click deposit or internal
transfer. Very simple. Both of the ways
would just put the money into the
account. So, in my email, I will now get
the login credentials to this account.
This account will [music] give me the
login to where I am actually going to
place the trade. So once again, trading
view is just to analyze the markets
where I'm interested in determining if I
want to buy or sell a market.
>> The broker is where I deposit the money
into where it's where my money is stored
and it will automatically connect me to
the third platform which is the PayPal,
the MetaTrader where you actually
execute the trade. So, in my email now,
I'm going to have the login to this
account, right? So, let me go ahead and
log into this account. Going to screen
record this on my phone. So, we're going
to go here to MetaTrader 5. Once you go
to MetaTrader 5, this broker section
will pop up. So, as we can see here on
our screen, our server is going to be 1x
trade server.
>> Okay.
>> Right. So, we're going to search up here
our server. As you can tell, it says
enter company or server name. [snorts]
So, you're going to search up 1x trade.
We click search and as you can tell that
is the server that we have. Now what is
our login account number? So this is our
account number 330245.
and then our password is our password
that we got in our email which we'll
just paste it on there. And then you
obviously want to save your password
always. And then you click done. Now
that's it. Now we officially have
everything. We have the trading view
where we analyze the trades, the broker
where we deposit the funds and then the
actual platform where we execute the
trades on which is Metatrader. So here
we have $10 with a 1 to500 leverage. As
you can tell we have just done an
internal transfer into here and this is
obviously a real live account. There's
no trades that have been taken in the
past. This is where you will go ahead
and depending on the market that you
analyze. For example, let's go back to
the market, which is EuroUSD. So, you've
determined that you wanted to buy
EuroUSD once price came back and had a
retracement into here. So, let's
hypothetically pretend like we're ready
to do that. So, we have EuroUSD.
So, as you can tell in all these markets
we have here, none of these markets are
U EuroUSD.
>> So, we're going to go ahead and search
it up. We go to this top section over
here. We're going to enter the symbol
which is euro USD
and we just click on this little tab
button right here which we're going to
add that button and then it'll pop up
down here at this bottom section. Okay,
>> as you can tell we have Euro USD. Now we
can trade click the chart details
statistics or delete it. Now the only
button we will ever really be clicking
here is trade. If you click on chart, it
will simply just take you to the same
chart that you're already seeing on
Trading View. Okay?
>> So, it's just a different way of looking
at it. [music] If you were to click on
details, details just shows you the type
of sector, industry, just really
unnecessary information that will do
nothing for you. And then lastly, you
have statistics, which once again just
shows you different numbers that I don't
even know how to use. Right? So let's
say you actually want to go ahead and
enter a trade on EuroUSD. Okay, very
simple, right? You would come here and
you would click on the actual currency
market and you would click trade. Now
once you click trade, you have a couple
of different options that pop up. So you
already know based off of your analysis
that you're not interested in selling
this trade at all. So that button is
completely out of the picture. You want
to buy this market, right? So, you know
that you want to click buy, but you
can't just buy right off the bat. You
want to make sure that you're in an
instant market execution because you've
just done your analysis, price has come
back to your area, gave your entry
signal, you want to enter the trade
right away. [snorts] Now, there's
different types of market execution. So,
you can enter the trade right now or you
have buy limits, sell limits, buy stops,
sell stops, buy stop limits, sell stop
limits.
To be fully honest,
I don't use any of those.
>> I look the same.
>> I don't use any of them. I don't know
how any of them work. They are pointless
to me. I want to enter a trade now,
right? When like like literally now or
whenever I'm ready to enter the trade. I
don't want to set a market order. Some
people use that because, you know, they
want to enter, let's say, oh, put me
into Bitcoin once Bitcoin hits 80,000.
And let's say price is at 100,000. It'll
automatically enter them once it's at
80,000. For us, since we're more
technical traders, we're going to be
watching the markets at all times. We
want to make sure we enter off of what
we're seeing, not what the market does
without us seeing it. So that's why we
have the instant market execution. Next
here, this is going to be our lot size
where for this example is going to be
0.01.
This is the amount that we are risking
on this position, which is in this
example
a dollar, right? Then you have your stop
loss and then your take-profit. So if we
go back to trading view, let's
hypothetically say that price has had
this retracement. We are currently at
this area of interest. So we know where
we want to enter the trade and we've
already had our candlestick rejection.
Well, we need to have two things that
are very important. Your stop loss and
your takerit. Your stop loss and your
takeprofit are very important because
they're going to let you know where
you're going to exit the trade if you're
wrong or get out if you're right. Your
stop loss should always be placed below
the wick, which is this tail, that pivot
of the rejection candlestick.
>> And then the high point should be set at
the last high. It really is that simple.
Obviously, a bit more analysis goes into
it, but this is the simplistic approach
of it. Once you have your entry signal,
once you have that rejection, your
candlestick will go and be placed at the
bottom of that. Perfect example, if I
were to go to the left hand side over
here, let's say I'm entering off of this
rejection. Let's say we're going to be
using this rejection of this area of
interest right here. That's our
rejection candlestick. We have our stop
loss be below that wick. Our takerit
would have been the previous high, which
would have been this takerit right here.
As you can tell, take profit would have
been completely smashed.
>> Same exact thing would have happened
here. As you can tell, that would have
been our candlestick rejection. Our stop
loss would have been below. Take profit
would have been at the high. Take profit
smashed once again. Right? So, going
back to this current trade, we can tell
that our stop loss based off of where we
would have been interested in entering
the trade could have been something like
right here. Could have been somewhere
around here. and your takerit could have
been somewhere around here. Now, if you
notice to your right hand side, you have
the red number, which is your stop loss,
and you have the green number, which is
your take profit. So, what we're going
to do is literally get this number and
place it in the stop-loss area.
>> Okay.
>> So, if I were to come over here, right?
So, we go back to our trading view and
we click on the stop loss. The stop loss
would be what does that number say? 116
>> 1 point 1.1
>> yeah six
>> six
>> 330
>> 330 What's the take profit?
>> It says uh 1.1
>> 7950
>> 79
>> 50
>> 5 0 Now
deviation I don't even know what the
hell that is. I've never used that in my
life. All I do is place [music] stop
loss and take profit and at this point
we would click buy. So obviously right
now it says invalid stop loss and take
profit. It's not because we have an
invalid stop-loss or take profit. It's
actually because the market is closed.
>> Okay.
>> So, funny enough, the market actually
opens up in about 18 minutes.
>> But we can take a trade right now on
crypto. So, let's say Bitcoin. So, we'll
come here and we'll search up BTC. So,
we'll come here, add our BTC. Just for
example purposes, we will click trade.
And same thing, we won't put a stop loss
or put a take profit. We'll just click
buy. So, we accept our quotes, but we
don't have enough money in our account.
So, we would have to deposit a little
bit more funds into our account to
actually be able to take a trade on
Bitcoin just because of the cost to do
it. So, we'll come here. We'll hit
another internal transfer from this
account to this account. We'll deposit
the full $89.
Process the transfer.
And uh you see how fast that [__]
reflects.
>> Oh, wow. Like it's already I took like 1
second. So let's try and take the
Bitcoin trade again. Click trade 0.01.
We'll click buy. We accept. And [music]
we are now in the position.
>> Nice.
>> So we are officially up 11 cents on
Bitcoin buys. So it really is that
simple. So this section is where you
have the different types of markets that
you're actually interested in trading.
The chart of the market that you're
trading. This is where you actually see
your trade fluctuate. And this is where
you would see the history of your trade.
So, as you can tell, we did another
internal transfer. So, that pops up in
the history. And this is our trade. So,
now that we're in our trade, we can
continue to hold once it gets to our
take profit or stop loss. Or we could
close it. If you want to close it, we
just tap it. And we would click close
position. Modify if you want to enter
another trade or bulk operations. Bulk
operations is once you have more than
one position, you can close all of them
at the same time. Since we only have one
position open at the time, that's not
necessary.
>> Okay,
>> this little plus line to the top right
is if you want to take another trade,
but same thing if you can just go over
here and click on it.
>> So, at this time, you want to close it,
you click close or you can just continue
to hold.
>> Okay. So, I have a question going back
to the uh like the take profit and stop
loss.
>> You showed me on the trading view, if
you go back to really quick.
>> Mhm.
>> Um how it was a short uh previous point,
the highest point you said.
>> Mhm.
>> And then it smashed.
>> Mhm. Would it be ideal to put a takerit
or just like let it ride and only do the
stop loss just in case?
>> Yeah, that's a great question. I mean,
you always want to put a stop loss,
right? Because if you don't put a
stop-loss, you're prone to price. And
that's why a lot of people have this bad
perception about trading and they think
that trading is a scam or people lose a
lot of money with trading. It's because
people don't pre-calculate their risk
and they don't have an area where they
get out where they're comfortable with
losing a certain amount of their
account. That's where the, you know,
risking 1% 2% of your account is so
essential and so important to your
trading. So yes, I would always say
place a stop loss because you want to
make sure that you get out at an area
and only lose a certain amount of your
account. And same thing for take profit.
I would always place a takeprofit just
so you lock in profits and don't have
this neverending potential of, you know,
having
>> profits that you can never actually lock
in. Right? As a human, once you start
seeing money on the screen, you become
very emotional and then you end up not
wanting to close and wanting more and
more and more and more. So, I always
recommend to place both, especially for
beginners. Take profit and a stop loss.
So, we've been in this trade for about 2
minutes and now we're negative 20 cents.
How does that make you feel?
>> Neutral, man. It's 20 cents.
>> 20 cents, right?
>> Well, that's how you should feel with
any size account. And you want to make
sure that you trade with an amount that
you're comfortable with and that you're
okay with losing, right? So in this
example, we don't have a stop-loss. We
don't have a takerit as you can tell
right in this area right here. So we
have an uncertain amount of money that
we can potentially lose from this
market. So the correct thing to do for
us would go to modify position and place
our stop loss and obviously place our
takeprofit and then we would do that. So
we don't have to worry about the trade
and be thinking about it all day
>> and us having to be glued to the screen
and glued to the phone watching this,
right? So we know exactly if worst case
scenario this hits our stop loss, we
only lose 10 bucks.
>> We only lose 20 bucks. Something that
we're comfortable with losing. You're
supposed to feel that way.
>> So right now we're now we're up 50
cents. So it really is that fast. So we
were just negative 50 cents. Now we're
up 50 cents. And you know we're going to
get these profits and take them home,
right? So we're going to click on this
right here. Click close position. And we
want to make sure we can close. We
accept.
And just like that, we have just made
39.
>> So, we started off about 5 minutes ago
with $99. Now, we have $99.39.
It's that easy. That's where the money
came from from the market. We just took
a trade with our analysis with
everything. And now we have just made
39.
>> Nice. Now, you do this over the course
of weeks, months, years, and that's
where you end up becoming a profitable
trader and being able to do this
consistently from the markets. Now, if
you want to withdraw these funds, same
thing. You now go back to the client
portal. And now in the client portal,
let's just hit a refresh. Now, our
account balance reflects here as $99.39.
[music] If you want to go ahead and
withdraw funds, you can go ahead and
withdraw. You add your wallet
information and then you just withdraw
it.
>> Sounds good.
>> Really is that simple. It is same way
how it goes in, same way how it goes
out. So you once again you have your
trading view where you would analyze the
markets to see what the direction of the
market is. You have the broker where you
deposit the funds and then you have
MetaTrader where you execute it. And
then for you to get the money back into
your account, it's just backwards. Do
everything backwards. And just like
that, you've learned what 99% of traders
procrastinate. how to analyze the
markets, how to deposit into a trading
platform, and how to execute a trade.
Now, at this point, right now, you are
ahead of 80% of traders.
>> Nice.
>> You've taken the step to actually take
your first trade, and you know how to do
it. You realize that it's not as
complicated as you thought before,
right?
>> It's pretty easy.
>> There's just a lot of buttons. It could
be a bit overwhelming. Now, you are
missing one thing that traders are
missing, and it's a a strategy, right?
because you need a pattern that happens
in the markets over and over again in
order for you to actually extract money
from the markets week after week. Can
you go to the markets how we just did
now, make a simple analysis, enter a
trade, and get lucky? Sure, you could
make some money, you can also lose some
money, but the importance is having a
concept that works time and time again.
So, I have a community where I review
people's trades. I review the mistakes
that they're making. And most
importantly, I let them know what
markets I'm trading for the week ahead.
[music] Because you can have 150
different markets to trade from. But if
I can just [clears throat] narrow down
those 150 markets to five high
probability markets, your odds of
succeeding are a lot higher. And I also
have a winning community where we have
students in there discussing topics on
how to become a profitable trader. And
everybody has the same ambition. So at
this point, you're just missing a
strategy. And you know where to get it.
If you guys want to know more about my
strategy and about my community, check
out the link in description below. We
are doing calls every single week
reviewing people's trades and I'm
letting you know the winning trades for
the week ahead. You want to know more
about it, hit the link in description
below. Hope you guys enjoyed this video
and you guys have finally taken the
moment to actually enter your first
trade and stop procrastinating. If you
guys like this video, hit a thumbs up,
subscribe, and I'll see you guys in the
next video. Set to forget.